你被炒了
You're fired.
《我們的生活》前情提要
Previously on This Is Us...
-什麼  -也許我們該奮鬥各自的事業了
- What? - I think it's time we go at it alone for a while.
就一段時間  看結果如何
You know? See what happens.
抱歉  我的劇本上沒寫有停頓...
This doesn't say "Pause" on my script.
上面也沒寫爛呢  再看現在這個效果
Well, it doesn't say "suck" either, yet here we are.
我根本不是演戲劇的料
I'm not cut out for theater.
你總是這樣  懷疑自己
You do that a lot-- doubt yourself.
你們一直忙著不讓凱特吃得太多
You're so busy making sure that Kate's not eating too much...
凱文  冷靜一下
Kev, calm down.
總怕蘭德爾覺得自己是被領養的
...and Randall's not too adopted!
對不起  我本該在你身邊的  以後改正
I'm sorry. I should have been there, and I'm gonna be there.
我兒子平時放學後
Do you think that my son could play with
-能跟你家小孩一起玩嗎  -當然
- yours sometime after school? - Yeah.
每次我新認識一個黑人
Every time I met a new black person,
就在那個小本本上標記一下
I would put a mark in this notebook,
每次遇見一個黑人男子
and every time I met a black man,
我就會想他會不會是我親生父親
I wondered if that man could possibly be my father.
不行  寶貝  要先吃完香蕉
No, baby, you got to finish your bananas first.
想吃香蕉嗎  小凱  吃香蕉嗎
You want some banana? Kev, you want a little banana, too?
吃完就可以去找爸爸玩了  再吃點
Go in and see your daddy right now, okay? You have some more.
-傑克  牛奶好像沒了  -好
- Jack, I think we're completely out of milk. - Yeah.
-他就是不喝果汁  -行  我...
- He won't drink his juice. - Yeah, I'll, um...
-就想喝牛奶  -我下次帶點回來
- He just wants milk. - I'll bring some home.
要再吃點蘋果嗎  來吧
Do you want some more apples? Come on.
來  吃飽了要不要下來  好的
Come on. Here, do you want to get out of your chair? Yeah.
來吧
All right. Come on.
親愛的  你要去做文職
Babe, a desk job?
小貝  我們需要這份工資
Bec, we need the money.
你連領帶都沒有
You don't even own a tie.
三個小傢伙之家
話說
So...
你聽說了嗎
did you hear?
聽說了
Uh... yeah.
要在茶水間給桑德拉準備驚喜生日蛋糕
Surprise birthday cake for Sandra in the break room.
其實根本算不上什麼驚喜
You know, it's never, it's never a surprise.
還有一件事
Okay, also,
我升職了
I got promoted.
現在是項目經理了
Project manager.
-太好了  恭喜你  -謝謝
- That's great, man. Hey. - Thanks.
我想帶你一起
And I'm bringing you with me.
這個...
Oh. Um...
謝謝你  不過算了
thanks, but no.
-還是謝謝你  -怎麼算了
- But thanks. - No?
你先別聲張
Keep this quiet,
我準備自己出去闖
but I'm, uh, gonna go out on my own.
想自己創業
I want to start my own thing.
我知道很冒險  但是只要事業步入正軌
I know it's risky, but once I get things up and running,
我就能有更多時間陪孩子們了
I can spend more time with my kids.
好吧  要不這樣  先別急著拒絕
All right, how 'bout this: why don't you, um,
花幾天時間考慮一下
take till the end of the week,
-週末再答覆我  -真的不用了
- think about it. - I'm okay.
我不需要考慮
Don't need to think.
週末再說  好嗎
End of the week, okay?
成績單
-爸爸回來了  -回來了
- Daddy's home! - Hi!
爸爸  爸爸
Dad! Dad!
-爸爸  -小凱別鬧
- Dad! - Kev.
-爸爸  -小凱
-小子  -我有問題要問你
- Hi. Hey, buddy. - I need to ask you a question...
-稍等  -爸爸
- One second. - Dad!
-你快看  -已經做得這麼漂亮啦
- Watch this. - Hey, look-look at the progress you made, bud.
-吃完晚飯就幫你  好嗎  -寶貝
- I'm gonna help you out after dinner, okay? - Hi. Hi, baby.
-爸爸  -怎麼了
- Dad! - Yeah.
-我們有冰淇淋吃啦  -冰淇淋
- We're getting ice cream! - Ice cream!
-冰淇淋  -我答應他們的
- Ice cream? - I promised them.
冰淇淋  冰淇淋
Ice cream? Ice cream?!
又不是給我買的  不然你下次就抱不動我了
None for me if you want to be able to pick me up again.
瞎說  你這麼瘦
Please, you are tiny.
-就你嘴甜  -不過你答應買冰淇淋
- Right. Mm. - But ice cream must mean that the kids'
-是不是因為孩子們成績挺好  -沒有
- report cards came back and they were good? - No.
基本都是B和C  我沒轍了
Actually, mostly B's and C's. I caved.
不知道該怎麼辦  我額葉都疼了
I don't know. Parenting makes my cerebellum hurt.
你的什麼
Sorry, your what?
就是我的大腦中控制情緒的部分
It's the part of my brain that makes my emotions.
我做了太多三年級的科學作業了
I have been doing way too much third grade science homework.
不過你還是看看這個吧
But why don't you, uh, look at that.
蘭德爾的老師為什麼想見我們
Why does Randall's teacher want to see us?
不知道
I don't know.
好吧
Okay.
*你如此美麗*
*You are too beautiful*
*親愛的  我想對你說*
*My dear, to be true*
*我如此愚鈍*
*For one lucky fool*
*配不上你*
*To be with*
*你太過美麗*
*You are too beautiful*
*我如此愚鈍*
*And I am a fool*
*卻愛慕著你*
*For beauty*
恕我冒昧  如果太久不彈  鋼琴會很孤單
Hope you don't mind. Pianos get forlorn if you don't play 'em.
不  我完全不介意
No, of course I don't mind.
-你怎麼學會彈鋼琴的  -我爸教我的
- Where'd you learn how to play like that? - My dad taught me.
我爸是他爸教的
And his dad taught him.
爸爸  你能教我們彈琴嗎
Dad, can you teach us to play?
我也很想教
I wish I could.
可家堛滬絳眵茩M都被奶奶和凱特姑姑佔了
Grandma and Aunt Kate got all the music talent in the family.
我一向都只有肌肉發達
Me? I was always all knuckles.
你爸比較擅長其他方面
Yeah, well, your dad's got other skills.
以前我還能靠這個本事
Me, I managed to squeak out a couple of dollars
混幾口飯吃
on one of these back in the day.
主要是吹小號  什麼表演我都參加
Mostly trumpet, mm. Any gigs I could get.
你能不能來參加學校的職業日
Will you speak at my career day?
職業日能不能叫爺爺去
Can Grandpa speak at my career day?
我想不行  寶貝兒
I don't think so, baby.
只能一個人發言  我已經報名了
You're only allowed one speaker, and I'm already signed up.
我想讓爺爺講
I pick Grandpa.
他的工作很酷
He had a cool job.
你是說老爸的工作就不酷了嗎
What are you saying, that Daddy doesn't have a cool job?
你們很喜歡到辦公室找我玩  不是嗎
But you guys love visiting me at the office, right?
我喜歡坐在你的椅子上轉圈
I like spinning in your chair.
其實你的工作有點無聊  爸爸
You kind of have a boring job, Dad.
基於長期氣候模式的商品期貨交易
Trading commodity futures based on long-term weather patterns
才不會無聊  好嗎
is not boring, okay?
抱歉
Sorry,
一聽"商品"這個詞我就有點犯困
sort of fell asleep soon as I heard the word "commodity."
凱文叔叔  你能在我的職業日上發言嗎
Uncle Kevin, can you speak at my career day?
老爸會負責職業日  討論到此結束
Daddy's doing career day! End of discussion.
我的發言會很"燃"的
And it's gonna be lit.
"燃"這個字不是這麼用的  對吧
That's not how you use "lit," right?
對
No.
對不起  我不明白
Sorry, I don't understand.
你們是說蘭德爾很有天分嗎
So you are saying that Randall is gifted?
可他成績很一般啊
But his grades are average.
你確定給他做的測試沒問題嗎
Are you sure you tested him right?
傑克  我們知道他有多聰明
Jack, we know how smart he is.
那他的成績是怎麼回事
Okay, so what's up with his grades?
也許是...  老師對他有偏見
M-Maybe is the-the teacher prejudiced?
-傑克  -不可能
- Jack. - No.
如果孩子在測試中表現良好
When a child tests well
成績卻反映不出來
but his grades don't seem to reflect it,
通常是他所在的學校沒有足夠的挑戰
oftentimes, he isn't being challenged at his school.
或許你們可以考慮其他選擇
And you maybe want to consider other options.
海恩斯學院
招收超常兒童
他們對蘭德爾這類特殊兒童
They have wonderful programs
由一套出色的學習方案
for exceptional children like Randall.
絕對不行
Not gonna happen.
傑克  你能不能冷靜點
Jack, please stop making me say "Jack."
雖然蘭德爾在的這所學校只有幾個黑人孩子
Randall is one of the only black kids at this school,
可他在這兒至少還有兄弟姐妹
but at least here he has his brother and sister.
-我明白  -那另外兩個孩子呢
- I know. - What about them?
他們也能去那所學校嗎
I mean, can they go, too?
皮爾森先生  恕我冒昧
Mr. Pearson, all due respect,
凱文和凱特過去是沒什麼好處的
Kevin and Kate wouldn't do well in that school.
看到沒  這就是你們犯的錯誤
You see, that's where you're wrong.
我們的三個孩子都很出眾
All of our children are exceptional.
我能摸摸你嗎
Can I touch you?
我只想再觸摸你一次
I just want to touch you one more time.
哪怕...  只是你身體的一部分
Just... one part of your body.
你的頭髮
Your hair.
我想清醒過來
I want to wake up...
對不起  我...  我...
I'm sorry, I... I'm...
我不能...
I'm not...
對不起  可以重來一遍嗎
I'm sorry, can we... can we just start over?
好的  凱文  能問你個問題嗎
Yeah, yeah. Uh, Kevin, can I ask you something?
當然
Yeah.
為什麼...
Why...
你能不能試著給我解釋一下
Just try to help me understand this.
為什麼每到這個場景
Wh-Why, every time we come to this scene,
這場戲悲傷到極點  本應該...
this-this pinnacle of grief, which should rip...
我是說  你本該讓觀眾們痛哭流涕
I mean, literally rip... tears from the audience,
你語氣怎麼像谷歌地圖的語音一樣毫無感情呢
why you summon up all the emotion of a Google Maps voice.
好吧
Right.
我不知道  可能...
I don't know. May...
可能台詞有問題
You know, maybe it's in the words.
你怎麼知道
How would you know?
你從沒說過那段詞
You've never said them.
沒有啊  我...  我正說著呢
Uh, no, I think... I think I'm saying 'em.
不對  你是  說了幾句
No. I mean, yeah, like, s-some.
說了點
Kind of.
可你大多都改了
But you're-you're mostly paraphrasing.
-對不起  -沒事沒事
- I'm sorry. - Y-Yeah.
你看  其實很簡單
You see, it's really simple.
奧利維亞就是傑西卡  你的妻子
Olivia is Jessica, your wife.
-又來了  -你就是大衛
- Okay. - You are David.
你愛她
You loved her,
可現在她死了
but now she is dead.
所以你正為失去她而悲痛不已
So you are grieving the loss of her.
你的世界都崩塌了
There's no longer any such thing as gravity.
你有沒有失去過什麼人
Have you ever lost anyone?
有
Yes.
可我不相信你
Because I don't believe you.
知道嗎  羅恩  我的工作
Well, you know, Ron, it's not my job
不是要讓你來相信我
to make sure you believe me.
不  不對  就是這樣
Oh, yes, yes, it is! It is!
這就是你的事
It is exactly your job!
做好你該做的事
Do your job.
她在寫什麼
What is she writing?
你寫什麼呢
What are you writing?
寫她的絕命書
That's her suicide note.
好了  好了  你們都夠了  好嗎
All right, all right, enough, okay?
他能做到的
He'll get there.
好吧
Okay.
好
All right.
週二上午十點  大家再來
10:00 A.M. Tuesday, everybody.
-多謝你  -隻是必要的過程
- Thank you. - It's a process.
先別再想了
Just... let it go for now.
好
Yeah.
你明天有什麼安排
What are you doing tomorrow?
我打算花一整天時間
Oh. Uh, well, tomorrow I was just gonna spend
感受我的失敗  不過...
the entire day feeling like a failure, but, uh...
跟我去派對吧
Come to a party with me.
派對  你說什麼派對
A party? What kind of party we talking?
-我會把地址發給你  -好吧
- I'll text you the address. - Yeah, okay. All right.
我去  不是吧
There's no way in hell.
這工作最好值得我費勁爬上去
This job better be worth it.
再見了  世界
See ya, world.
以前的日子真好
It's been real.
天啊
Oh, Jesus.
你真的沒事嗎
You sure you're all right?
對  我很好
Oh. Yeah, I'm good.
我很好  真的
I'm good. Yeah. Yeah.
沒事
I'm good.
羅森塔爾太太
Mrs. Rosenthal...
叫我馬琳
Marin.
馬琳
Oh. Marin.
我知道我之前在我哥哥手下的工作經歷
I realize that my previous employment with my brother
可能和這份工作不是很相符
might not be directly applicable.
可是我這人做事條理分明
However, I am abnormally organized.
1997年美國電影
男主角患有潔癖強迫癥並憎惡同性戀
我就是《盡善盡美》中
And I'm basically the not crazy version
正常版的傑克·尼科爾森
of Jack Nicholson in As Good as It Gets.
-我超喜歡那部電影  -是嗎
- Oh, I love that movie. Oh. - Right?
"你讓我想成為更好的人"
"You make me want to be a better man."
抱歉
Oh! Sorry.
抱歉  你剛才說...
I'm sorry, you were saying...
對  我有補助金的寫作經驗
No. I-I have grant writing experience,
而且經常和好萊塢的一些人打交道
and I'm used to dealing with Hollywood types,
我知道他們是你們基金的主要捐助者
which I know are large contributors to your foundation.
我還知道  你是"保持聯絡"
And I know you're on the board of Stay In Touch
和"蝴蝶舞會"的董事會成員
and the Butterfly Ball.
我的天  真是太厲害了
Oh, my God, that's amazing.
作家  藝術家  木偶表演家
道格·金凱德Doug Kincaid,
在你哥哥之前  他是你老闆  對嗎
your boss before your brother, was it?
他對你稱讚有加
He speaks about you in such glowing terms.
你為什麼要離開他的公司
Why did you quit his firm?
因為我愛上了他
Because I fell in love with him,
所以我們不適合一起工作
and it was not a healthy situation.
我喜歡你  凱特
I like you, Kate.
你能勝任  你很聰明
You're qualified, you're smart,
而我現在正需要一個助手
and I need someone right now by my side.
但並不是做助理的工作
Now, it's not assistant work.
既要協調活動  又要拓展業務
It's part event coordinator, part development associate.
榮幸之至
I would be absolutely thrilled.
不過你可能還得替我辦些私事
But there is some personal stuff you may have to do,
有時跑跑腿
an errand here or there,
開車接送我女兒
maybe drive my daughter to and from?
好啊  沒問題
Yeah. Okay.
-偶爾的  所以別擔心  -當然不會
- Not much, so don't worry about that. - No, of course.
那麼  你接受這份工作嗎
So, do you want the gig?
等等  真的嗎
Wait, really?
我太激動了
I'm so excited!
我也很激動
Well, I'm so excited!
從衛生紙粘住你頭的那一刻起
I wanted you from the moment
我就已經決定要你了
the toilet paper was stuck to your head.
說真的  不管你需要什麼
Seriously, though, whatever you need,
我都願意去做
I'm your girl.
這是我女兒  傑瑪  這位是凱特
This is my daughter. Jemma, this is Kate.
你雇了個胖子啊
So, I see you picked the fat one.
我們的生活
第一季  第六集
天氣衍生品是一種貿易商品
Weather derivatives are tradable commodities
它能夠保護企業所有者
that protect business owners
免受天氣變化的影響
from future changes in the weather.
就好比你舔一下披薩
It's like licking a piece of pizza
別人就不會吃了
so that nobody will eat it later.
我開始想披薩了
Now I'm thinking about pizza.
-好吧  -不  等等  抱歉  等一下
- Okay. - No, wait, I'm sorry-- no, no, no, wait,
我這次是想搞清楚的
I was gonna get it this time.
如果連我的老婆孩子都不理解我是做什麼的
Look, how am I supposed to inspire an auditorium full of strangers,
我又怎麼能打動一個禮堂的陌生人呢
and my own wife and kids don't even understand what I do?
-不是這樣的  -真的嗎
- That's not true. - Really?
我是做什麼的
What do I do?
你買賣天氣
You trade weather.
你根據天氣類型交易商品
You trade commodities based on weather patterns.
這又是什麼意思呢
And what does that mean?
該死  蘭德爾  我不知道
Oh, damn, Randall, I don't know.
你用閃電球交換雷暴雲
You swap lightning bolts for thunder clouds?
我知道你每天都是怎麼度過的
Look, I know what your day is like.
我知道你喜歡其中一個合夥人
I know that you like one of your partners
卻討厭另外一個
and you hate the other one.
我知道你打算重新設計辦公室的傢俱
I know that you're gonna redesign your office furniture
你還有可能解雇你的助理
and that you might fire your assistant
因為她總是說"好像"
because she says "like" too much.
她說個不停
It's nonstop.
我能和你深入地探討一下天氣類型嗎
Can I talk to you in depth about weather patterns?
不行  我做不到
No, I cannot.
即便我能  你也不會答應的  所以...
But I don't think you'd want me to if I could, so...
你到底怎麼了
Hey, what's-what's this really about?
或許我本該成為一位音樂家
Maybe I was meant to be a musician.
不好意思  你說什麼
I'm sorry, what now?
或者藝術家  或者作家
Or an artist or a writer.
想想看  貝絲
Just think about it, Beth.
也許我身上是有這種天賦的
There's this whole genetic side of me
只是根本沒人發現
that nobody even knew existed.
我是說  威廉是個詩人
I mean, William was a poet,
藝術家  音樂家
an artist, a musician.
也許我一直很有藝術天賦
You know, maybe I've had an artistic side in me all along
可沒人發掘出來
and nobody knew to empower it.
或許我不該做一個
You know, maybe I wasn't meant to be
每天必須西裝革履
a straight and narrow math geek
中規中矩跟數字打交道的呆子
destined to wear a shirt and tie every day
就像我父母想像的那樣
like my parents thought.
也許我這輩子就該做個音樂家
Maybe I was meant to live a musician's life.
到處奔走  在酒吧媞t奏
On the road and playing clubs, you know?
好吧  在你這個音樂家的夢中
All right, well, in this musical fantasy version of yourself,
-你演奏哪種...  -薩克斯
- what instrument would you... - Sax.
1990年美國爵士樂電影
就像《愛情至上》中的韋斯利
Like Wesley in Mo' Better Blues.
一定得是薩克斯
Definitely sax.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
真是太性感了
That's sexy, yeah.
你在笑話我
You're making fun of me.
-沒有  -有  你就是在笑話我
- No. - No, you're making fun of me.
不  沒有  我沒有啦
No, I am not. I'm-I'm not.
你親生父親剛回到你的生活中
Your biological father just came back into your life,
這激起了你的很多想法
and it's bringing up all kinds of stuff.
這  這很正常
It's-it's normal.
聽著
Look,
你不妨試試展示下自己狂野藝術家的一面
why don't you try out this-this crazy artist side
在這次發言中一鳴驚人
of yourself and, you know, get this presentation popping.
看看八歲小觀眾們喜不喜歡  好嗎
Let's see how it flies with some eight-year-olds, right?
在你真的改行
Before you, like, shift careers
去夜場演奏薩克斯風之前先實踐下
and start playing open mic saxophone nights.
-也許我真會去  -那好啊
- You know, maybe I will. - Okay, yeah.
我知道你在笑話我  不過我會試試的
I see you are making fun of me, but I will.
沒有  好啊
No, yeah.
-你能不能不笑了  -我停不下來
- Why don't you stop smiling? - I can't.
-別笑了  -抱歉
- Stop smiling. - I'm sorry.
我忍不住  這中年危機早期癥狀太像你了
This early midlife crisis is so you, I can't stand it.
你想再來點笑料嗎
You want something to smile about?
-不要了  拜託  -真的  真的嗎
- No, please. - Do you, do you really?
你好  麻煩找下麥克爾
Hi, can I speak to Michael please?
唐納  我是凱特
Hey, Tanner, it's Kate.
對  凱文的妹妹  你最近怎麼樣
Yeah, Kevin's sister. How are you?
很好  想問下你會不會剛好有空
Oh, good. Are you by any chance
來參加個慈善會
available on the third for a charity event?
我有個問題想問下你
Hey, I have a question for you:
你對無家可歸現象怎麼看
how do you feel about homelessness?
我明白  很糟糕  對吧
I know, it's a bummer, right?
我們差不多要接待四百人
So, we're looking to cater about 400 people.
您的餐廳勢必也想加入到我們的活動
Your restaurant's definitely gonna want to be a part of this.
天啊  我知道
Oh, my-- I know.
太棒了  行  很好
Awesome, okay, great.
謝謝  澤  拜拜
Thanks, Z. Bye.
你太能幹了
You're killer.
我要你載我去艾希莉家
I need you to take me to Ashley's.
讓凱特載你去怎麼樣
Oh, well, what if Kate gave you a ride?
可以嗎
Do you mind?
行
No.
抱歉
Sorry.
我在車媯尼A  實習生
I'll be in the car, intern.
-要進去了嗎  -好
- Should we go in? - Yeah.
這到底是個什麼派對
Listen, what kind of party is this anyway?
大家看著都很難過的樣子
'Cause everyone seems pretty sad.
當然難過了
Of course they're sad.
這是場追悼會
It's a memorial service.
快點  我們進去吧
Come on, in we go,
不然好吃的奶酪要沒了
before all the good cheese is gone.
海恩斯學院
我們來這兒幹嘛
What are we doing here?
我們來這
We are here
是因為你妻子  還記得她嗎
because your wife-- do you remember her?
應該記得
I think so, yeah.
你愛她勝於生命的那個人
The one that you love more than life itself?
-想起來了  -那就好
- Definitely rings a bell. - Got it.
她想看看這地方
She wants to take a look at this place.
好吧  我在看呢
Okay, I'm looking.
天啊  這地方比蘭德爾
Geez, this place is whiter
之前那滿是白人的學校還要"白"啊
than Randall's already pretty white other school.
看看這些孩子
I mean, look at these kids.
他們就像小小的納粹機器人
They look like little nazi robots.
那小孩還拎了個公文包
That one's got a briefcase.
我說  哪有孩子拎公文包的啊
I... no kid should be carrying a briefcase.
我覺得很可愛啊
I think it's cute.
是  你現在是覺得可愛  往後他餘生
Yeah, it's cute now; next thing you know, he's gonna be
都要被困在辦公室的小格子堣F
trapped in a cubicle for the rest of his life.
我告訴你吧  先是拎個公文包
I tell you, it starts with a briefcase,
接著再繫上個領帶  坐上辦公桌
then you put on a tie, you sit at a desk.
接下來你猜怎樣  你就被束縛在日光燈下了
Next thing you know, you are so conditioned to the florescent lights
你走到外面  連太陽都會刺痛你的眼睛
that when you step outside, the sun actually burns your eyes.
真的嗎
Really?
我說的不是自己
This isn't about me.
肯定也不是說蘭德爾吧
Well, it certainly isn't about Randall.
我  我本來不打算在有初步規劃前
Look, I... I wasn't gonna say anything
把事情說出來的  不過...
until I'd had a few details worked out, but...
我打算自己出來混了
I think I'm gonna go out on my own.
自己開公司
Start my own company.
三個小傢伙之家  我只是...
Big Three Homes. I just...
現在說可能有點不合時宜
Doesn't feel like a very good time right now.
我覺得挺好的
I think it's great.
你應該去試試
I think you should do it.
沒那麼簡單的  小貝
It's not that easy, Bec.
這個地方得花多少錢
I mean... what does this place even cost?
我們會想到辦法的
We'll figure it out.
會有辦法的  我們可以讓蘭德爾換一所學校
We'll figure it out-- we'll send Randall to another school,
給他請個家教  盡我們所能
we'll get him a tutor, we'll do whatever we have to do.
好  我只希望你能快樂
All right. I just don't want you to be unhappy.
-我說真的  -明白
- I mean it. - Okay.
那就好
All right.
我們會再回來的
We'll come back.
這兒很漂亮
This is nice.
非常漂亮
It's very nice.
傑瑪  你媽媽說你會告訴我
Jemma, your mom told me that you would be giving me
艾希莉家的地址
Ashley's address.
傑瑪  你能不能回答我的問題
Jemma, will you answer me?
傑瑪  我需要地址
Jemma, I'm gonna need the address.
-幹嘛  你急著回去工作嗎  -是的
- Why? 'Cause you need to get back to work? - Yes.
要不是看重這份工作
And if I didn't value the work,
我也不會甘願忍受你這態度了
I wouldn't be tolerating this attitude.
只是澄清下
Just so we're clear.
她跟你說什麼了  讓你當合夥人嗎
What'd she tell you, you'd be an associate?
你真以為我媽媽會因為
And you thought my mom was gonna
一些三流明星接你的電話
give you actual responsibilities,
就給你真正的職位嗎
because a few C-list celebrities take your calls?
很顯然  她雇你
Clearly she only hired you
只是因為她覺得一個胖女孩會走進我的內心
because she thinks the fat girl can get through to me.
我猜她是覺得  越胖越好吧
Guess she figured, bigger the better.
其實我覺得你挺可憐的
You know, I actually feel bad for you.
搞什麼鬼
What the hell?
你別可憐我  好吧
Yeah, well, don't feel bad for me, okay?
因為我還有車回家
'Cause I have a ride home.
什麼意思
I'm sorry?
-下車  -什麼
- Get out. - What?
給我下車  傑瑪  不然我把你扔出去
Get out of the damn car, Jemma, before I toss you out of it!
你知道嗎  你可以走路去艾希莉家
And you know what? You can walk to Ashley's.
給你分享胖女孩的心得  如果你走得快
And fat girl to fat girl, if you keep up the pace,
走路一小時可以燃燒417卡路里
you can burn 417 calories an hour walking.
我太愛美式奶酪了
I love American cheese.
英式奶酪吃起來總是很沮喪  太煩了
English cheese is so blue, it's angry.
美式奶酪就好像是可以躺上去的床
American cheese is like a-a bed you can just fall into.
話說回來  這是誰的告別聚會
So, whose good-bye party is this anyway?
弗蘭克·彭德格拉斯
Frank Pendergrass.
三天前他在中央公園慢跑時
Tree branch fell on him three days ago
樹枝砸在了他身上
when he was jogging through Central Park.
就這麼死了
Bang. Dead.
這也太倒霉了
Well, that sucks.
你怎麼認識他的
You knew him how?
我不認識  訃告上寫了追悼會的地址
Oh, I didn't. No, the obituary gave the address of the service,
於是我就...
so, I thought...
等一下
Hold on a second.
你是什麼意思
What are you trying to say?
你好
Hello.
我是弗蘭克的妻子  格蕾絲
I'm Frank's wife, Grace.
你好  我叫傑西卡
Hi. Uh, I'm Jessica.
這是我丈夫  大衛
This is my husband, David.
你們是我丈夫的學生嗎
Were you students of my husband?
我們其實是在他的課上相識的
We actually met in his class.
是吧
Right?
他學生
Students.
當時我們坐在第一排
Yeah, we were sitting in the front row,
一直眉來眼去的
and we kept looking at each other,
最後弗蘭克看不下去了  停下來說道
and then finally Frank stopped the class and said,
"你們倆太讓我分心了  出去  上個床
"You two are distracting me. Go outside, have sex,
準備好學知識了再進來"
and come back when you're ready to learn something."
還真像弗蘭克會說的話
Well, that sounds like Frank.
弗蘭克
Frank.
謝謝你們的到來
Thank you both so much for coming.
-感謝你的到來  -節哀順變
- Thank you for coming. - I'm so sorry for your loss.
謝謝
Thank you.
任務完成了
Well done.
不不不  等等  你把我
No, no, no, hold on. No, no, no. You brought...
你把我帶到一個陌生人的葬禮上來
You brought me to a stranger's funeral?
-追悼會  -管它叫什麼  為什麼
- Memorial service. - Whatever. Why
因為我演不好苦情戲嗎
What, because I'm struggling with the grief scene?
你說過我會演好的
You said I would get there.
是啊  但我可沒說憑你自己能演好
Yeah, well, I didn't say you'd get there on your own.
這也太瘋狂了
This is insane.
但是十分感謝你的這一課
But thank you very much for the lesson.
我很感激  現在我要去喝杯酒
I appreciate it. Now I'm gonna go have a drink.
好好享受你的奶酪吧
Enjoy your cheese.
華特迪士尼於1967年製作並發行的動畫電影
寶貝  怎麼不看《森林王子》了
Hey, baby, what happened to Jungle Book?
演完了
It's over.
媽咪悄悄來洗個澡  噓
Well, Mommy snuck in a quick shower-- shh.
一分一秒的時間都不能浪費呀  小可愛
Got to get them in while you can, little bug.
你真漂亮
You're so pretty.
謝謝  寶貝
Thank you, baby.
如果我漂亮你也漂亮  因為我們長得很像
Well, if I'm pretty, you're pretty, 'cause we look alike.
能不能把媽媽的黃色襯衣拿來
Oh, can you get Mommy's yellow blouse,
帶紐扣的那件
the one with the buttons?
就在衣櫥  謝謝
Just in the closet? Thank you.
S號
XL號
謝謝  寶貝
Thank you, bug.
我去接蘭德爾
Okay, I'm going to pick up Randall.
再見  小美人
Good-bye, beautiful.
一會兒見  寶貝  還有
Bye, see you later. Hey, baby,
我馬上就準備好了
I'm almost done getting ready.
今晚  小傢伙  我們一起拼B-52飛機
Tonight, little man, you, me and a B-52?
別做完了  我也要來拼一點
Okay, don't finish it, I got to help with something.
可以呀
Sounds good.
抱歉  我是在  我在...
I'm sorry. I was, I was, uh...
大家一直送我吃的  好像我不會做飯一樣
People keep bringing me things, like I forgot how to cook.
冰箱都放不下了
There's no room in here
我也不知道把弗蘭克的食物放哪兒
and I don't know where to put all of Frank's food.
好多醃黃瓜
You have a lot of pickles.
我討厭醃黃瓜
I hate pickles.
但是他超愛的
But he loves them.
他在床上吃
Yeah, he eats them in bed.
曾經
"Ate."
現在他是過去式了
He is now past tense.
以前可以直呼其名
He used to be "is."
現在都要加個曾經
Now he is "was."
我喜歡醃黃瓜
Hey, I like pickles.
那太好了
Good.
-給你  -好
- Here. - OK.
你喜歡節日領帶嗎
How do you feel about holiday ties?
還有運動外套
And sport coats.
因為我問過傑埵怳F
Because I asked Jeremy,
他說不需要任何他爸爸的遺物
but he said he didn't want anything of his dad's.
傑埵怞h大了
How old is Jeremy?
十五歲
Fifteen.
這太殘忍了
That's tough.
十五歲的話太殘忍了
15 is tough.
我小時候
Uh, my dad and I
我和我爸會一起拼模型
used to build models together, when I was a kid.
是嗎
Yeah?
是的  我們會拼飛機  輪船
Yeah, we'd build, um, planes and boats.
我以前總是挑最難的拼
I used to pick the most complex ones,
B-52轟炸機  航空母艦
B-52s, aircraft carriers,
因為做這些花的時間最長
'cause they took the longest, you know?
我們家有三個孩子
See, I was one of three kids,
所以真得花心思去爭取和爸爸獨處的時間
so you really had to strategize to get your alone time with Dad.
最後
You know, and eventually,
我們建了一整只艦隊
we had a whole fleet of them;
一排一排地在架子上陳列著
We had just rows and rows, shelves of them.
當他去世以後...
You know, and then when he died...
當...
when...
當他去世後  我...
when he... when he died, I, um...
我把這些模型都扔掉了
I-I threw all the models away.
我把每一個都扔掉了
I threw every one of them away.
我也不知道我為什麼要這樣做
I don't know why... why I did that, you know?
那時你多大
You were how old?
那是很久以前了
Uh, it was a long time ago.
我還留著...
I have, um...
我還留著這個
I have this.
這個項鏈  這是他的
This necklace, this is his and, um,
我就只留了他這條鏈子
it's the only thing I have left of him.
最開始  我並不想戴
And at first, you know, I didn't want to wear it,
我不會戴  甚至都不想看  但現在...
I wouldn't wear it, I wouldn't even look at it, but now it's...
我只有這了  我不能取下來  所以...
It's all I have and I... I can't take it off now, so...
沒事的
It's okay.
天哪  這實在太蠢了
Oh, my God, this is so dumb.
我在做什麼  我該來安慰你才是
What am I doing? I'm supposed to be comforting you,
而不是把鼻涕流你身上到處都是
not snotting all over you.
你叫什麼來著
Who are you again?
蘭德爾  你爸爸來了
Randall, your daddy's here.
我們馬上完了
We're almost done.
三局兩勝
Best two out of three.
好
Okay.
謝謝你讓他來你家玩
Hey, thanks for -- thanks for having him.
他想來  我隨時歡迎
Oh, I will take him as much as he'll have it.
讓我家孩子也看看什麼叫禮貌
Show my own boys what manners look like.
麗貝卡告訴你  他在學校的事了嗎
Hey, did Rebecca tell you about his school?
沒有  怎麼了
No. What happened?
他好像是考試得了很高的分
I guess he scored off the charts on some tests,
現在校方想把他送走
and now they want to uproot him during the school year,
送去私立學院什麼的
send him to some private academy.
把他和其他兩個孩子分開
You know, take him away from the other two.
為什麼  那是個寄宿學校嗎
Why? Is it, is it a boarding school?
不是
No.
就是
No, it's, uh--
就是穿制服什麼的
it's uniforms and,
身邊全都是白人小孩
a lot of little white kids
搞得那媢閉O在德國納粹一樣
marching around like it's Nazi Germany.
我明白了
Oh, I see.
所以你才向我咨詢
That's why you're running this by me.
什麼
What?
你想找一個黑人批准你在育兒方面
You're looking for me to give you the black person seal of approval
做一個糟糕的決定
for any messed-up parenting decision you make.
怎麼就糟糕了  我只是...
How is it messed up? I just--
不想讓我兒子覺得自己更特殊而已
I don't want my son to feel more different.
所以就因為他是黑人  你就想阻礙他的發展
Okay, so you just want to hold him back because he's black?
不  當然不是了
No. Absolutely not. I...
傑克
Jack,
蘭德爾是個特別的孩子
Randall is special.
如果你讓他放棄如此好的一個機會
So, if you're looking for somebody to make you feel better
還期待別人會來安慰你
about denying him a special opportunity,
你還是另找一位黑人吧
you may just have to find yourself another black person.
再見了  夥計們
See you, guys.
準備好啦
Ready, Freddy.
再見  伊薇特夫人
Bye, Ms. Yvette.
-贏了嗎  -當然
- Did you win? - Yep.
當我把她的孩子送到她懷堮
And I'll never forget the look on her face
她的表情我永生難忘
when I placed her child back into her arms.
永生難忘
Never.
這就是我的工作
So, yeah, that's what I do.
日復一日地
Day in and day out,
將像你們這樣的孩子從火堭洏X來
I save children, just like you guys, from fires.
謝謝
Thank you.
大家為肯德爾的媽媽曼迪鼓掌
Let's give it up for Kendal's mom, Mandy! Yeah.
下一位是苔絲的爸爸  蘭德爾
All right, okay, uh, up next is Tess's dad, Randall,
他是位氣象員
who is a weatherman.
抱歉抱歉
Oh, sorry, sorry.
說錯了
Uh, strike that.
他是位天氣交易員
He's a weather trader.
我不知道這是幹什麼的  聽他解釋吧
I don't know what that is, but I think he's gonna tell us.
歡迎蘭德爾
Here's Randall.
你們好
Hey, y'all.
我是天氣交易員
I'm a weather trader,
我知道這個很難解釋
which I know can be a little bit hard to explain,
於是
and so, um,
我給你們寫了首歌
I wrote you guys a song about it.
爸爸不是不會彈鋼琴嗎
I thought Daddy couldn't play the piano?
爸爸的確不會啊
Daddy cannot.
*如果你*
*If you*
等等  等一下  抱歉
Wait, mm, hold on one second. Sorry about that.
天吶
Oh, sweet Jesus.
若你...
If you...
請稍等
Mm. One second, please.
*若你有家農場*
*If you've got a farm*
*你該知道玉米未來的成本*
*You should know the future cost of corn*
*所以簽一個承包合同*
*So buy yourself a contract to*
*保護自己的莊稼吧*
*Protect your crops.*
*驟雨  風暴或降雪*
*Rain, storm or snow*
*也許會影響*
*Might affect your*
*夏日作物收成  那麼*
*Summer crops, so*
*明智地投資*
*Invest your money wisely*
*你就得以安全...*
*You'll be safe...*
大家一起來
Come on everybody.
*若你有家農場*
*If you've got a farm*
*你便知道玉米未來的成本*
*You should know the future cost of corn*
*所以簽一個承包合同*
*So buy yourself a contract*
別看他  別看
Look away. Just look away.
*保護自己的莊稼吧*
*To protect your crops.*
你在這堸
Ah, there you are.
我剛和格蕾絲在一起
I was with Grace.
誰
Who?
格蕾絲  弗蘭克的妻子
Grace. Frank's wife.
為什麼
Why?
因為她很悲傷  她丈夫過世了
Because she's sad. Her husband died.
你為什麼跟我兇
Why are you mad at me?
因為我們不該來的
Because we shouldn't be here.
這不是一場戲
This is not a play.
她是一個真實的人
You know, she's a real person.
我也是一個真實的人
I'm a real person.
我能看出來  終於看出來了
Yeah, I can see that-- maybe for the first time.
你經歷過什麼
What happened to you?
我父親過世了
What happened is my dad died.
就是這樣
That's what.
而我因此痛恨他
And I hated him for it.
我曾一個月無法進食
And I couldn't eat for a month,
我曾每日醒來以淚洗面
and I used to wake myself up crying,
這樣就可以再次在淚水中入眠
so I could cry myself back to sleep again.
這就是我的經歷
That's what happened.
你為什麼將這些情感撇開
Why do you push all of that away?
這些不是你害怕的妖怪
You can't just kill the feelings
你無法扼殺自己的情緒
like they're some creature that you're afraid of.
這種痛楚是你的一部分
That pain is a part of you.
我現在能看出來
I can see it now.
也能感覺到
I can feel it.
抱歉  吃過醃菜
Sorry, pickle mouth.
我不介意
I don't care.
傑瑪還好嗎
Is Jemma OK?
什麼  她很好
What? She's fine.
她說今天和你相處得很愉快
She said she had a really nice day with you.
但我根本不信
Which I didn't believe for a second,
因為你沒有回來  所以我追問了她
because you didn't come back, so I pressed.
丟下她  我很抱歉
I am really sorry that I left her.
如果你想以遺棄兒童罪起訴
I can understand if you want to press charges
我可以理解
for child abandonment.
天吶  快別這麼說
God, don't even worry about it.
我自己還曾把她丟在三大百貨
I've left her at Three Malls myself,
而且不止一次在高速路上
and I've wanted to shove her out of the car
想把她從車堨嵽X去
on the freeway at least once.
我都不知道拿她怎麼辦了
I don't know what to do with her anymore.
我走不進她的內心
I can't reach her.
昨天之前
Before yesterday,
她在兩周堨u和我說過七個字
she's spoken seven words to me in two weeks.
你也聽到了
And you heard them:
"你雇了個胖子啊"
"I see you hired the fat one."
這是你雇我的原因嗎
Is that why you hired me?
不  天吶  當然不是
No! God, no.
不全是這樣
Not entirely.
我猜就是
Yeah, I thought so.
我也知道這樣不好
I am not proud of it.
我很抱歉  但那真不是唯一的原因
I am sorry and it's really not the only reason.
見你本人之前  我就很喜歡你的簡歷
I-I liked your resume before I met you.
但  確實
But, yeah.
我覺得你可能會...
I thought that maybe you'd be able to...
理解她
understand her.
理解她的問題
Her issues.
天吶  我這樣說出來
Oh, my God, it sounds horrible
太傷人了
when I say it out loud.
天吶  拜託別辭職
God, please don't quit.
別再讓我處理私人事務了
No more personal stuff.
你看到我工作  瞭解我的能力了
You saw my work; you know I can do it.
別再讓我開車帶傑瑪了
No more driving Jemma around.
你可以雇一個助手代勞的
You can afford an assistant for that.
-成交  -我要加入蝴蝶舞會
- Done. - And I want to chair the Butterfly Ball.
-可以  -我還要一間辦公室
- It's yours. - And I want an office.
-沒問題  -我還想要一個實習生
- Okay. - And I want an intern.
好吧  太過了
Okay, too far.
明天九點見
I'll see you at 9:00 tomorrow.
謝謝
Thank you.
傑瑪還在這媔
Hey, is Jemma still here?
在外面
She's outside.
好的
Okay.
喂喂  皮爾森公司
Hello? Hello? Pearson Corporation.
想談一單大生意嗎
Would you like to discuss the big deal?
我太忙了  你回頭打給我吧
Well, I'm too busy. You'll have to call back.
喜歡過來和爸爸一起工作  是不是
You love coming to work with Dad, huh?
我想讓你來幫我一些忙
I wanted you here because I need your help with something.
過來
Come here.
這是什麼
What's that?
這是公司負責在建的房子
That is a house the company's working on.
-真酷  -是啊
- Cool. - Yeah.
你看
You see, uh...
你看  我不知道  建這面牆需要多少
You see, I don't know how many feet of two-by-four
寬四寸厚二尺的板材
I'm gonna need for this wall right here.
你知道三英尺是多少...
You see how each... how each inch is...
多少英吋嗎
is three feet?
22.5英尺
22h feet.
真了不起  小傢伙
That's pretty cool, buddy.
沒想到你數學這麼好
Didn't know you were so good with numbers.
等等  過來
Wait, wait, wait. Come here.
那這面牆呢
What about this wall right here?
建這面牆需要多少
How many... how many do I need for that?
這個我不會算
I don't know that one.
一秒鐘前你還會算  現在不會了嗎
You knew how do it a second ago, now you don't?
我不知道  爸爸
I don't know it, Dad.
你肯定會算
I think you do.
我不會
I don't.
蘭德爾  別鬧了
Randall, that's enough.
-過來  -我不想算
- Come here. - I don't want to.
看  就是這面牆
Look. This wall, right here.
我需要多少板材
How much do I need?
-我不知道  不知道  -把答案說出來
- I don't know. I don't know. - Tell me the answer.
多少英尺  快告訴我
How many feet? Tell me right now.
我不知道
I don't know.
見鬼  蘭德爾  快說答案
Damn, it, Randall, tell me the answer!
34英尺
34.
說什麼
What's that?
34英尺
34.
很正確
That's right.
你為什麼要假裝不會算這些題呢
Why are you pretending not to know this stuff, huh?
故意在數學中考個B
Getting B's in math?
不讓別人知道你很聰明
Not letting people see how smart you are?
我不想和他們不一樣
I don't want to be different from them.
和誰不一樣  學校堥漕ヱ臚l嗎
Different from who? Who, the kids at school?
如果得了A  我就有冰激凌吃
If... if I get an A, I'll get ice cream,
而凱特和凱文沒有
and Kate and Kevin won't.
他們會恨我的
And then they'll hate me.
我能跟你說實話嗎
Can I be honest with you?
男人間的對話
Man to man?
你媽媽和我總是盡力
You know, your mom and me, we always try
對你們幾個一視同仁
to treat you kids the same.
一向如此
Always have.
但並不總是有效
Hasn't always worked, because, well,
因為你們本來就不一樣
you're not all the same.
你是我們領養的  我們沒好好談過這事
You're adopted, and we don't talk about that enough.
因為對我來說  你完全就是我兒子
'Cause to me, you are every part my son.
也許...我不想讓你覺得自己太突出
Maybe I.. I don't want you to feel like you stand out.
但是你得知道一件事
But I need you to know something.
我希望你出類拔萃
I want you to stand out.
我希望你們每一個都能
I want all of you to be as different
與眾不同
as you can possibly be.
做最好的自己
In all the best ways.
我傾盡全力愛你  孩子
I love you as much as a human heart can, kiddo.
你是個出眾的年輕人
You are an exceptional young man.
別讓你爸卑微的想法
So don't let your dad's poor choice
阻礙你展現自我
make you feel afraid to be different.
好嗎
Okay?
好
Okay.
把手指放上去彈彈  聲音更美妙
It sounds better when you put your fingers on it.
在電影
You know how, in the movies,
主角不擅長一件事
when somebody's bad at something,
但又不想這樣
but they don't want to be,
於是就下定決心練習
and so they set their mind to it.
然後通過蒙太奇的剪輯手法
And then we see this montage
無數遍的練習鏡頭呈現在觀眾眼前
of them practicing and practicing.
而到了最後的關鍵時刻  就會大放異彩
And then comes the big moment, and they're amazing,
大家歡呼喝彩
and everybody cheers.
我看過這類電影
I've seen a few movies like that, yeah.
我可能跳過了"蒙太奇"部分
I think I skipped the montage.
你第一次告訴我你的工作時
When you first told me what you did for a living,
天  我一個字也聽不懂
man, I didn't understand a word.
對天發誓
Hand to God, I mean,
你還不如說些德語什麼的
you might as well have been speaking German.
但當時我看著你的表情
But I was watching your face.
我沒吸毒的時候  我曾與幾位
In my better days, I have met and played with
世界頂級音樂家一起演奏過
some of the greatest musicians in the world.
當他們談起音樂
And when they talked about music,
他們的表情看起來
their face looked like your face
和你談起工作時的表情一模一樣
when you told me about whatever the hell it is you do.
但是如果有幫助  我可以教你彈一兩段琴
But if it'll help, I can show you a thing or two on the piano.
那就太棒了
That would be great.
-今晚就算了  -對啊
- Oh, not tonight, just... - Oh, right.
-現在太晚了  -是啊  算了
- It's late is the thing. - Yeah. No.
我明白
I got ya.
晚安
Good night.
Night.
你不用和我告別
You don't have to say bye to me.
我沒辭職
I didn't quit.
我明白你的感受
I know what you're going through.
別想著和我促膝談心了
Stop trying to have a moment with me.
我媽以前很苗條  也很漂亮
So, my mom was skinny and gorgeous.
現在也很漂亮
Well, is gorgeous.
大家還是喜歡搭訕她
She still gets hit on by everyone.
有一次她得了流感  還被人問起
She once was asked if she was a model
是不是模特兒
when she had the flu.
在這樣的媽媽身邊長大非常艱難
Pretty hard growing up with a mom like that.
我一直不斷拿自己和她作比較
I spent all my time comparing myself to her,
然後把氣撒在她身上
and then I took it out on her.
現在我們幾乎不說話了  很糟糕
And now we barely talk, and it sucks.
你媽不完美
Hey, your mom's not perfect.
她有她的問題  你有你的問題  但是
She has her stuff, and you have yours, but...
你別再跟她對著幹了
you got to cut her a break.
不然你會後悔的
Or you're gonna regret it.
我保證
I promise.
凱特  能配合一下嗎
Kate, will you please help me out?
不  我討厭這件裙子
No, I hate this dress!
我知道  可是我不管你討不討厭
I know. I don't care that you hate it, though.
就這一件合身的乾淨衣服
It's what's clean and what fits,
-你穿定這件了  -我恨你
- and it's what you're wearing. - I hate you!
快穿上  我們要遲到了
Put it on, please; we're running late.
傑克
Hey, Jack?
-蘭德爾  你們準備好了嗎  -好了
- Randall? You guys are ready? - Yeah.
-五分鐘後得出發了  -我知道  有我呢
- We have to leave in five minutes. - I know. I got him.
你確定嗎
You sure about this?
對  我確定
Yeah, I'm sure.
聽你媽媽的話
Hey, listen to your mother.
你看上去棒極了
See, you look great.
拿好你的午飯  小姑娘
Come get your lunch, young lady.
謝謝
Thank you.
-看清沒有  -嗯
- See it? - Yeah.
需要點時間練習
Yeah. Takes a little time,
不過你會掌握竅門的
but you'll get the hang of it.
看著我
Here, look at me.
真精神
Looking sharp.
準備好上學第一天了嗎
You ready for your first day?
凱特和凱文會跟我們一起走嗎
Are Kate and Kevin gonna ride with us?
我們先把他們送到學校
We're gonna drop them off,
然後再把你送到學校
then we're gonna drop you off,
放學後  我們再一起回家
and then we'll all be back together
-好嗎  -好
- after school, okay? - Okay.
等等  過來
Hey, wait. Come here.
往下系點
We'll tuck this low.
這樣好看又舒服
Nice and comfortable.
去跟你媽說再見
Say bye to your mom.
新鮮出爐的煎餅來了
Hot, plump ones coming through.
媽  今天放學後我要去練足球
Mom, I have a soccer practice after school today.
我記得
Yeah, I remember.
過來
Come on.
我有話要說
I have something to say.
我父親每天都會系領帶
Uh... my dad put on a tie every day
因為他必須這樣做
because he had to.
我每天系領帶  是因為我想這樣
I put one on every day because I want to.
這點很重要
It's important you know that.
也許我不用每天靠出入火場來維持生計
Maybe I don't run into burning buildings for a living,
但對我來說  我的工作同樣驚險刺激
but to me, my work is challenging and exciting.
也許別人很難理解
I will not apologize for the fact
但我不會因此道歉
that it's hard to explain to people.
好的  老爸
Okay, Daddy.
還有  威廉
Uh, also, William,
謝謝你願意教我彈鋼琴
thank you for offering to teach me piano,
但我覺得
but I don't think at this point
鑒於我們現在的關係
in our relationship it would be healthy
還是先別這麼做了
to introduce that dynamic.
所以
And so,
下週二開始  我要去上
starting next Tuesday, I'm gonna be taking piano lessons
帕金斯女士的鋼琴課
from Mrs. Perkins down the road.
春天會有一場演奏會
There's gonna be a recital in the spring,
我希望你們都能來支持我
and I hope that you will all come and support me in this.
剛才是怎麼回事
What was that?
那是中年危機  親愛的
That was a midlife crisis, baby.
這還不算什麼  接著吃華夫餅吧
But just a little one, so go on, eat your waffle.
"還不算什麼"  說得真好
"Just a little one." That's good.
他竟然要學鋼琴
He-He's gonna take piano?
給你買了杯咖啡
Brought you a cappuccino.
牛奶換成豆奶  對嗎
Soy, yeah?
你太貼心了
You're too kind.
我還想說...
Also wanted to say that, uh...
我想說  我原諒你了
You know, I wanted to say that I forgive you.
那節"課"的事...
For the lesson. Um...
我能說什麼呢  奏效了
What can I say? It worked.
我覺得也是
Mm, I'd say it did.
不過課可不止那一節
But, um, that's not the only lesson.
不是嗎  好吧
No? Okay.
我們之間發生的事...
What happened between you and me...
永遠不會再發生了
is never gonna happen again.
我以為...
Oh. I-I thought...
我知道  但我們僅僅只是這種關係
I know you did, but this is who we are and all we are.
你是我丈夫  我是你的亡妻
You're my husband, and I'm your dead wife.
你永遠不會再和她上床了
And you will never sleep with her again.
這讓你作何感想
Now, how does that make you feel?
悲傷
Sad.
好極了
Great.
用上這種情緒
Use that.
我加入
I'm in.
三個小傢伙之家
那隱形傳輸是怎麼回事
So what was that about teleportation?
隱形傳輸和冷空氣
Yeah, the teleportation and the freeze breath
或是熱空氣
or, like, hot breath.
玩得開心
Hey, have fun.
再見  爸爸
Bye, Dad.
愛你
Love you.
字幕組
ZiMuZu.tv
原創翻譯  雙語字幕
僅供學習 禁止用於任何商業盈利行為
最新最快海外影視字幕下載
請登陸www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻譯:  青椒  moonshine7  小蘿莉  Tracy-旋子
翻譯:  小尼克  小應子  桑葚  冬麟  克奡
校對:  兔牙Bobby貓  不高興童鞋
時間軸:  格瑞特  ccisoda
後期:  寶寶  精校&總監:  紅楓Gabriel